
NAME
    Set-PSBreakpoint
    
SYNOPSIS
    Sets a breakpoint on a line, command, or variable.
    
    
SYNTAX
    Set-PSBreakpoint -Command <string[]> [[-Script] <string[]>] [-Action <scriptblock>] [<CommonParameters>]
    
    Set-PSBreakpoint [-Script] <string[]> [-Line] <Int32[]> [[-Column] <int>] [-Action <scriptblock>] [<Common
    Parameters>]
    
    Set-PSBreakpoint -Variable <string[]> [[-Script] <string[]>] [-Mode {Read | Write | ReadWrite}] [-Action <
    scriptblock>] [<CommonParameters>]
    
    
DESCRIPTION
    The Set-PSBreakpoint cmdlet sets a breakpoint in a script or in any command run in the current session.  Y
    ou can use Set-PSBreakpoint to set a breakpoint before executing a script or running a command, or during 
    debugging, when stopped at another breakpoint.
    
    Note: Set-PSBreakpoint cannot set a breakpoint on a remote computer. To debug a script on a remote compute
    r, copy the script to the local computer and then debug it locally.
    
    Each Set-PSBreakpoint command creates one of the following three types of breakpoints:
      -- Line breakpoint:  Sets breakpoints at particular line and column coordinates.
      -- Command breakpoint:  Sets breakpoints on commands and functions.
      -- Variable breakpoint: Sets breakpoints on variables.
    
    You can set a breakpoint on multiple lines, commands, or variables in a single Set-PSBreakpoint command, b
    ut each Set-PSBreakpoint command sets only one type of breakpoint. 
    
    At a breakpoint, Windows PowerShell temporarily stops executing and gives control to the debugger. The com
    mand prompt changes to "DBG>", and a set of debugger commands become available for use. However, you can u
    se the Action parameter to specify an alternate response, such as conditions for the breakpoint or instruc
    tions to perform additional tasks such as logging or diagnostics.
     
    The Set-PSBreakpoint cmdlet is one of several cmdlets designed for debugging Windows PowerShell scripts. F
    or more information about the Windows PowerShell debugger, see about_Debuggers.
    

PARAMETERS
    -Action <scriptblock>
        Specifies commands that run at each breakpoint instead of breaking. Enter a script block that contains
         the commands. You can use this parameter to set conditional breakpoints or to perform other tasks, su
        ch as testing or logging.
        
        If this parameter is omitted, or no action is specified, execution stops at the breakpoint, and the de
        bugger starts.
        
        When the Action parameter is used, the Action script block runs at each breakpoint. Execution does not
         stop unless the script block includes the Break keyword. If you use the Continue keyword in the scrip
        t block, execution resumes until the next breakpoint. 
        
        For more information, see about_Script_Blocks, about_Break, and about_Continue.
        
    -Column <int>
        Specifies the column number of the column in the script file on which execution stops. Enter only one 
        column number. The default is column 1. 
        
        The Column value is used with the value of the Line parameter to specify the breakpoint. If the Line p
        arameter specifies multiple lines, the Column parameter sets a breakpoint at the specified column on e
        ach of the specified lines. Windows PowerShell stops executing before the statement or expression that
         includes the character at the specified line and column position. 
        
        Columns are counted from the top left margin beginning with column number 1 (not 0). If you specify a 
        column that does not exist in the script, an error is not declared, but the breakpoint is never execut
        ed.
        
    -Command <string[]>
        Sets a command breakpoint. Enter command names, such as "Get-Process" or function names. Wildcards are
         permitted.
        
        Execution stops just before each instance of each command is executed. If the command is a function, e
        xecution stops each time the function is called and at each BEGIN, PROCESS, and END section.
        
    -Line <Int32[]>
        Sets a line breakpoint in a script. Enter one or more line numbers, separated by commas. Windows Power
        Shell stops immediately before executing the statement that begins on each of the specified lines.
        
        Lines are counted from the top left margin of the script file beginning with line number 1 (not 0). If
         you specify a blank line, execution stops before the next non-blank line. If the line is out of range
        , the breakpoint is never hit.
        
    -Mode <VariableAccessMode>
        Determines the mode of access that triggers variable breakpoints. The default is Write. 
        
        This parameter is valid only when the Variable parameter is used in the command. The mode applies to a
        ll breakpoints set in the command. 
        
        Valid values are:
        
        -- Write: Stops execution immediately before a new value is written to the variable. 
        
        --  Read: Stops execution when the variable is read, that is, when its value is accessed, either to be
         assigned, displayed, or used. In read mode, execution does not stop when the value of the variable ch
        anges.
        
        --  ReadWrite: Stops execution when the variable is read or written.
        
    -Script <string[]>
        Sets a breakpoint in each of the specified script files. Enter the paths and file names of one or more
         script files. If the files are in the current directory, you can omit the path. Wildcards are permitt
        ed.
        
        By default, variable breakpoints and command breakpoints are set on any command that runs in the curre
        nt session. This parameter is required only when setting a line breakpoint.
        
    -Variable <string[]>
        Sets a variable breakpoint. Enter a comma-separated list of variables without dollar signs ($).
        
        Use the Mode parameters to determine the mode of access that triggers the breakpoints. The default mod
        e, Write, stops execution just before a new value is written to the variable.
        
    <CommonParameters>
        This cmdlet supports the common parameters: Verbose, Debug,
        ErrorAction, ErrorVariable, WarningAction, WarningVariable,
        OutBuffer and OutVariable. For more information, type,
        "get-help about_commonparameters".
    
    -------------------------- EXAMPLE 1 --------------------------
    
    C:\PS>set-psbreakpoint -script sample.ps1 -line 5
    
    Column     : 0
    Line       : 5
    Action     :
    Enabled    : True
    HitCount   : 0
    Id         : 0
    Script     : C:\ps-test\sample.ps1
    ScriptName : C:\ps-test\sample.ps1
    
    Description
    -----------
    This command sets a breakpoint at line 5 in the Sample.ps1 script. As a result, when the script runs, exec
    ution stops immediately before line 5 would execute.
    
    When you set a new breakpoint by line number, the Set-PSBreakpoint cmdlet generates a line breakpoint obje
    ct (System.Management.Automation.LineBreakpoint) that includes the breakpoint ID and hit count, as shown i
    n the following sample output.
    
    
    
    
    -------------------------- EXAMPLE 2 --------------------------
    
    C:\PS>set-psbreakpoint -command Increment -script sample.ps1
    
    Command    : Increment
    Action     :
    Enabled    : True
    HitCount   : 0
    Id         : 1
    Script     : C:\ps-test\sample.ps1
    ScriptName : C:\ps-test\sample.ps1
    
    Description
    -----------
    This command creates a command breakpoint on the Increment function in the Sample.ps1 cmdlet. The script s
    tops executing immediately before each call to the specified function.
    
    The result is a command breakpoint object. Before the script runs, the value of the HitCount property is 0
    .
    
    
    
    
    -------------------------- EXAMPLE 3 --------------------------
    
    C:\PS>set-psbreakpoint -script sample.ps1 -variable Server -Mode ReadWrite
    
    Description
    -----------
    This command sets a breakpoint on the Server variable in the Sample.ps1 script. It uses the Mode parameter
     with a value of ReadWrite to stop execution when the value of the variable is read and just before the va
    lue changes.
    
    
    
    
    -------------------------- EXAMPLE 4 --------------------------
    
    C:\PS>set-psbreakpoint -script Sample.ps1 -command "write*"
    
    Description
    -----------
    This command sets a breakpoint on every command in the Sample.ps1 script that begins with "write", such as
     "write-host".
    
    
    
    
    -------------------------- EXAMPLE 5 --------------------------
    
    C:\PS>set-psbreakpoint -script test.ps1 -command DiskTest `
      -action { (if $disk -gt 2) { break } }
    
    Description
    -----------
    This command stops execution at the DiskTest function in the Test.ps1 script only when the value of the $d
    isk variable is greater than 2.
    
    It uses the Set-PSBreakpoint cmdlet to set a command breakpoint on the DiskTest function. The value of the
     action is a script block that tests the value of the $disk variable in the function.
    
    The action uses the BREAK keyword to stop execution if the condition is met. The alternative (and the defa
    ult) is CONTINUE.
    
    
    
    
    -------------------------- EXAMPLE 6 --------------------------
    
    C:\PS>set-psbreakpoint -command checkpoint-computer
    
    Id       : 0
    Command  : checkpoint-computer
    Enabled  : True
    HitCount : 0
    Action   :
    
    C:\PS> function CheckLog {
    >> get-eventlog -log Application | 
    >> where {($_.source -like "TestApp") -and ($_.Message -like "*failed*")}
    >>}
    >>
    C:\PS> Checklog
    DEBUG: Hit breakpoint(s)
    DEBUG:  Function breakpoint on 'prompt:Checklog'
    C:\PS>>>
    
    Description
    -----------
    This command sets a breakpoint on the CheckLog function. Because the command does not specify a script, th
    e breakpoint is set on anything that runs in the current session. The debugger breaks when the function is
     called, not when it is declared.
    
    
    
    
    -------------------------- EXAMPLE 7 --------------------------
    
    C:\PS>set-psbreakpoint -script sample.ps1 -line 1, 14, 19 -column 2 -action {&(log.ps1)}
    
    Column     : 2
    Line       : 1
    Action     :
    Enabled    : True
    HitCount   : 0
    Id         : 6
    Script     : C:\ps-test\sample.ps1
    ScriptName : C:\ps-test\sample.ps1
    
    Column     : 2
    Line       : 14
    Action     :
    Enabled    : True
    HitCount   : 0
    Id         : 7
    Script     : C:\ps-test\sample.ps1
    ScriptName : C:\ps-test\sample.ps1
    
    Column     : 2
    Line       : 19
    Action     :
    Enabled    : True
    HitCount   : 0
    Id         : 8
    Script     : C:\ps-test\sample.ps1
    ScriptName : C:\ps-test\sample.ps1
    
    Description
    -----------
    This command sets three line breakpoints in the Sample.ps1 script. It sets one breakpoint at column 2 on e
    ach of the lines specified in the script. The action specified in the Action parameter applies to all brea
    kpoints.
    
    
    
    
REMARKS
    To see the examples, type: "get-help Set-PSBreakpoint -examples".
    For more information, type: "get-help Set-PSBreakpoint -detailed".
    For technical information, type: "get-help Set-PSBreakpoint -full".

